TRACIE: Tonight was your first time
at the club, wasn't it?
JIM: No,
I've been there a few times before.
TRACIE: Really?
How come I haven't seen you?
JIM: I noticed you
the first night I walked in.
You always stand out.
TRACIE: (CHUCKLING) Well, thank you.
How come it took you till tonight
to talk to me?
You're not shy, are you?
JIM: Maybe a little.
JIM: Are you okay with this?
Just taking off with someone
you hardly know?
TRACIE: I trust myself.
JIM: What do you mean?
TRACIE: Well, I believe in human nature.
You know, that (SIGHING)
people are basically good.
JIM: You're right, most people are.
JIM: Tracie. You spell that
with a "Y" or an "I-E"?
TRACIE: "I-E". Guys are always
assuming I'm a "T-R-A-C-Y."
How I hate guys who assume.
JIM: Me, too.
TRACIE: You look like a James.
JIM: Nope, just Jim.
TRACIE: How about Jimmy?
JIM: No, just Jim.
TRACIE: Oh, come on, you are shy.
JIM: Look, uh, there's something
I have been meaning to tell you.
I think you have beautiful hair.
TRACIE: Oh, you think so?
JIM: Yeah.
PILOT: Brown Bag,
this is Brown Bird, we have audio-visual.
TRACIE: Do you think it's sexy?
Brown Bag, close into one click.
Oh, yeah. There's nothing sexier
than short hair on a beautiful woman.
What is it about big hair
that turns men on?
that turns guys on, anyway?
Bad taste. (LAUGHING)
Look at me. I want to see your eyes.
Innocent, just the way I like them.
That's him. That's our man.
SAM: Car is registered to a Jim Gelway.
MAN OVER RADIO:
Brown Bird, this is Brown Bag. Move in.
He's testing, Tracie. Tell him
he's got the Midas touch.
You got the Midas touch.
That's 'cause I'm God's gift to women.
And you know what I think you are?
I think you're a natural-born cocksucker
(UNZIPS PANTS)
and I think it's time you did
what you were born to do.
No.
- What is this?
- (GASPS)
- What the fuck is this?
- Oh, shit!
- Fucking bitch!
- Bust him!
SAM: Brown Bird, Brown Bag, move in!
Take him! Take him now! Now!
Pull your vehicle to the side of the road
and keep your hands
- where I can see them.
- Fuck!
Police! Pull over, now!
I got him, Alex.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(SCREAMING)
Call for help, now!
Tracie! Hold on! Don't move!
Stay where you are! Stay still!
(GROANING)
Tracie, hold on, we're going to get you!
- Come on, guys!
- MAN: There's nothing to hook on to!
- Give me a hand!
- Hold on!
Alex?
Tracie!
(WATER SPLASHING)
(BELL TOLLING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
- Hey, Hannah.
- Hi, Megan.
I hope we don't have that big math test.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
- MEGAN: Jezzie.
- Hey, Megan.
Jezzie, guess who called me again
last night?
Oh, let's see, um...
Ah! Good morning, Dimitri.
Hey, Megan, I downloaded some
really cool GIFs. You want to see them?
Yeah, sure. What are they?
We'll see inside.
Agent Flannigan.
Control, check in Starodubov and Rose.
Check!
Hey, Jezz, what do we call
the Ruskies these days?
Russians, former Soviets? I forget.
New World Order, Devine.
Get used to it.
Charles Lindbergh, Lucky Lindy,
or The Lone Eagle, as he was called,
is our subject today
because he was the first man to what?
- Megan?
- Fly over the Atlantic?
Very good. First man to fly solo,
non-stop from New York City to Paris,
and that was 1927.
An astonishing accomplishment.
Which brings us to today's assignment.
Let's see which of you can navigate,
or fly, if you will,
from our home base
to our hero's website here
in the fewest number of links.
All right, and you're off.
(ALL TYPING)
That's very clever, Dimitri.
Megan, might I have a word with you?
- Save me a seat, okay?
- Okay.
Come to my office.
Take a seat.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Now, Megan, you know I understand
the particular pressures of your life.
Your father being who he is.
The enormous expectations,
all adds up to rather a lot, doesn't it?
- Yes, sir.
- Mmm.
But none of that excuses
your breaking the honour code.
What?
I know all about you and Dimitri, Megan.
We don't tolerate cheating, now, do we?
Cheating?
Mr Soneji, there's been a mistake.
We only pass notes, you know,
jokes and stuff.
Megan, before you go any further,
best have a look at that.
Mr Soneji?
Yes?
This essay, it isn't mine.
Beg your pardon?
What do you mean?
Oh, my...
Oh, dear girl, I'm...
Oh, dear, dear...
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(AIR HISSING)
(DOOR RATTLING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Gary, why is the door locked?
Oh, my God! What happened?
She's collapsed. She's just collapsed.
I'll tell you what,
you stay with her, I'll get some help.
Okay. Megan? Hey, sweetheart,
can you hear me? Megan?
(GASPING)
- Hey, Jezzie.
- Hi, Kila.
- Hey, Hannah, where's Megan?
- She's with Mr Soneji.
Control, I'm en route
to Soneji's classroom.
I'm sure it's just a meeting
that went long.
Well, it's against procedure.
Mr Soneji should know better.
His office.
Mr Soneji? Secret Service, open up.
Mr Soneji?
Do you have a key?
I'm sorry, there seems to be
something stuck in here.
Stand back.
Control, shut down. Stop all vehicles.
Lock on Soneji and Rose.
So, how many of these boats
you have to make
before you become shipshape?
I have never seen a man
work so hard at looking busy.
Alex, it's been eight months.
It's time you forgave yourself.
Vickie,
you know that forgiving yourself
is the one thing a person cannot do.
REPORTER ON TV:
...choose to make contact.
We are currently trying
to put the pieces together
as to how and why this man
would murder a teacher
and kidnap a young student.
Here's a photograph
of the missing student.
Megan Ann Rose is 12 years old.
Blonde hair with hazel eyes.
She's 3'5" tall,
and weighs about 52 pounds.
She was last seen inside the school,
with the suspect, around noon today.
We have just received information that
senior FBI and Secret Service officials
have arrived at the family home
of Senator Rose.
We will go there live
as soon as we have our satellite feed.
Technicians are setting up extra
telephone lines at the Rose home,
all in preparation, should the kidnapper...
(WATER SPLASHING)
(MEGAN MUMBLING)
Mom...
Please.
I want to go home.
The FBI and police are on the lookout
for this man, Gary Soneji.
This is a recent school photograph...
REPORTER 2:we only know
that he has disappeared
with the 12-year-old daughter
of Senator Hank Rose,
how and why is on the mind of...
REPORTER 3: Police are trying
to find out who this man really is,
his motives for killing
teacher Amy Masterson
- and the kidnapping of Megan Rose.
- (PHONE RINGING)
We go back live to join reporter
Alison Peretsky,
who has been at the scene
since law enforcement officials arrived.
ALISON: Thank you, Jamie.
It's now approximately four hours
since this tragic story unfolded...
Yes?
MEGAN: Mom...
Please.
I want to go home.
Hello?
You tuned into me, Dr Cross?
That sounds like Alison Peretsky
at WNKW Action News.
Gary Soneji?
That'll do for now.
How did you get this number?
Unlisted numbers?
Come on, Alex, there's no such thing.
It's all out there in the air,
you just have to know how to grab it.
Hey, how do you feel about
my kidnapping being bigger news
than your little tragedy there
with Jim Gelway?
You know, you really ought to
give an interview
about what happened that night.
You know what they say
about sharing your pain, it's
very cathartic.
Thanks, but I'm doing okay.
Well, see, now, that's good to hear.
That's very good.
I thought for a while there you wouldn't
be able to get your act back together
and that would be a great shame.
I have been planning
for a long, long time
to involve you in the fate
of our Little Miss Muffet.
Megan.
Do you have trouble saying her name?
First name rapport?
Is that Hostage Negotiations 101?
Now, come on, Alex, you can
do better than that, can't you?
Do you think you're going
to dissect me in three blinks of an eye?
I'm not that easy.
But with a little patience and a little help,
you just might profile me to a T.
What makes you think I'm interested?
They say that when I die,
the case will die.
They say
it will be like a book that I closed.
But the book, it will never close.
Very poetic. What the hell is it?
Uh, I have left you something
for your visit with the Roses tonight.
You'll find it in your cold,
corrugated
mailbox.
It's time to get back to work, Dr Cross.
SONEJI: I have been planning
for a long, long time
to involve you in the fate
of our Little Miss Muffet.
ALEX: Megan.
Do you have trouble saying her name?
(REPORTERS MURMURING)
Sorry, Detective, this is a federal case.
I've been invited.
Bobby.
Sir, we have a detective down here
who may have a piece of evidence
pertinent to the case.
KYLE: Alex?
Special Agent Craig. Well, I'll be.
Dare I ask?
In my mailbox.
Anything else?
That'll get you inside.
Terry.
Get this to McArthur.
- Who's in charge?
- Ollie McArthur.
Pedigree FeBe, made his bones
busting wackos in the Seattle office.
Soneji. Clean?
Clean? Squeaky.
Fibres look generic, fingerprints, nada.
The whole school's
a goddamn forensic vacuum.
All he left us was
one very neatly strangled teacher.
Heads are gonna roll
at the Secret Service.
Oh...
Jezzie Flannigan, Alex Cross.
Agent Flannigan was in charge
of the Secret Service detail at Cathedral.
- Dr Cross.
- Agent Flannigan.
I've read your books on profiling.
Obviously not close enough, but...
Kyle, this shoe was IDed by the Roses.
It's Megan's.
Dr Alex Cross,
Special Agent in Charge...
- Oliver McArthur.
- How do you do, sir?
Alex, I'll catch you later.
- Forensics.
- Yes, sir.
The Senator and Mrs Rose
are through here.
But before we talk to them,
have you any idea
why Soneji is involving you?
Not at all.
This way.
Excuse me, shouldn't Agent Flannigan
be in the room with us?
Not a good idea.
Miss Flannigan is not welcome.
But she's a material witness.
She failed the Roses
and she failed the Service.
I think Agent McArthur has a point.
No, he's missing the point.
You saw Soneji every day,
five days a week for how long?
Two years.
You have no idea
how much you know about this case.
Agent Flannigan...
SONEJI: They say that when I die,
the case will die.
They say
it will be like a book that I closed.
But the book, it will never close.
ALEX: Very poetic. What the hell is it?
SONEJI: I have left you something
for your visit with the Roses tonight.
You'll find it in your cold,
corrugated mailbox.
- (TURNS TAPE OFF)
- (RAINING)
Well, for what it's worth, that's Soneji.
His speech pattern's the same.
Is he, um...
Are we dealing with a sex maniac?
Someone who might, you know...
No, sir.
This man has no such interest
in your daughter.
She's merely a means to an end.
What do you mean?
I see no standard procedure
in anything he's done.
MCARTHUR: I disagree.
This is a professional kidnapping.
It's going to be about money.
Which is good.
But you're saying it isn't about money?
I think he wants to draw this out.
From what he's said,
whatever his motives,
it's very unusual.
What did he mean about the book?
That it will never close?
I honestly don't know.
Well, I think I do.
Let me tell you what this
Gary Soneji is up to.
The last thing he wants
is good crisis management.
What he wants is to confuse.
Rancour, mixed signals, disorientation,
those are his tools.
So he calls a local cop.
A damaged cop
shouldering some heavy baggage.
He's using Dr Cross as his messenger.
Excuse me, the man that
kidnapped our daughter didn't call you,
so your agenda is what,
to insult the man he did call?
- Mrs Rose, I never intended...
- No, you wait a second.
A mad man has our daughter
and for some reason
he contacted this man.
Do you know why?
No, ma'am, not yet.
ALEX: Hello.
You okay?
You, uh, got any tips
for helpless situations?
- Well, you could smoke a carton a day...
- (CHUCKLES)
...or you could bounce back.
Yeah, well, I don't see
anywhere to bounce to.
Like to get out of here?
(HORNS HONKING)
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
What did McArthur mean
when he referred to you as damaged?
Last summer I let a sting operation
get out of control.
My partner was killed.
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
Hey, Megan. How are you?
Lovely to see you.
Do you recognise my voice?
It's me.
Mr Soneji.
Mmm-hmm.
I brought you that.
A lovely cup of tea with honey.
I know your throat is sore.
It'll make you feel better.
There you go.
It's all right.
You have nothing
to be scared of, Megan.
I'm not scared.
Good.
But you're wondering what's going on.
I know what's going on,
you're a kidnapper
and you're a sick weirdo.
(LAUGHING)
Megan, you're the most opinionated girl
in my class.
- Think you got that from your mom?
- I want to go home.
You will.
Just promise me
you're going to behave yourself, okay?
That's all.
Now, listen, if you need to use
the bathroom, or anything at all,
just press that, okay?
I want to go home! Now!
Look, I brought you some fresh clothes.
- Please! Mr Soneji, please!
- (DOOR CLOSES)
This is a fine gun.
It's Turkish.
Handmade, 1924.
That is nice.
My daddy won it in a game of poker.
Aces and Eights.
Dead man's hand.
That's about as much as I know
about my father.
Have a seat.
(SIGHING)
Do you know of any relationship
between Amy Masterson and Soneji?
Amy? No way.
Why do you ask?
He strangled her.
It's an act of passion.
That's a demonstration of will.
A message.
Take me seriously. What do you see?
- Dr Cross...
- Alex.
Alex, women's intuition, third eye,
sixth sense, whatever it is, I don't have it.
Sure you do,
you just don't look at it right.
Every face has two aspects.
Now try looking at it down the middle
one side at a time.
Would you say this man was confident?
Yeah.
- Narcissistic?
- I wouldn't know.
- You ever see any flashes of hatred?
- No.
- Anger?
- Hostility?
- No.
Look,
everything about him was right.
He was always patient. He was pleasant.
He had a sense of humour.
I mean, he was the perfect teacher.
What do you see?
I see...
No, I mean about me.
What do you see about me?
And that's why you're here, isn't it?
To size me up?
Evaluate your primary material witness?
I see that you're about to start
an argument.
I need to help get her back.
What makes you think I want a partner?
- You don't.
- That's right.
- I can understand that.
- No, you can't.
Can I tell you why I don't care?
Shoot.
Look.
When I was assigned to Cathedral,
it was a job I didn't want.
It's a far cry from working rope-lines
or flying Air Force One
but I have been there for three years.
I have been responsible for Megan
for three years.
And that little girl means more to me
than even a partner.
Can you understand that?
I suppose so.
But even if I say no anyway,
you'll probably just
follow me around wherever I go.
So, if it's a choice between
having you as a partner or as a stalker,
I guess I'll take my chances
with a partner.
Thank you.
The student drop-off is there.
That's my morning post.
Student sign-in.
Cameras are there,
there, there and there.
Motion sensors all around the periphery.
Foolproof way to keep the kooks out.
Exactly, we were always looking
in the wrong direction.
Which door did he go out?
Uh, that one there.
It's a straight shot to his parking space.
Let's go in.
- His classroom.
- Mmm-hmm.
He was teaching the kids how
everything on the Internet is connected.
- MCARTHUR: Alex, you got a sec?
- Sure.
Listen, I think turf wars
are a total waste of time.
If I was out of line last night, I apologise.
Don't. I've been there.
- Anything you need, you let me know.
- Sure, Mac.
AGENT HICKLEY: Doctor Cross,
you might want to see this.
- This is Megan's desk?
- Yes.
What are you doing?
Scoping GIFs.
Graphic Interchange Formats.
They're all stego-encrypted.
Somewhere among the billions
of zeros and ones making up this image
is a string of text.
I know about this, it's the cutting-edge
method of passing notes in class.
It's driving the teachers nuts.
How long before you can access it?
Oh, try never.
You don't crack stego
without a password.
Would you take me to his office?
Oh, when you find Soneji,
ask him for the password.
He planted a monitoring virus
on the girl's hard drive.
Every keystroke Megan hit,
Soneji was recording it.
Good move, Jezz.
Angling for a position with the DCPD.
I like that.
Dr Cross, Agent Ben Devine.
Agent Devine
is security systems supervisor.
Well, for now.
We are going to be thrown to the wolves
as soon as they find Megan Rose
dead in a ditch.
Now what makes you so sure
that's what's going to happen?
Me getting fired or the girl in a ditch?
Sorry, I'm having a pessimistic day.
Tell me, Soneji, did he...
Did he ever show any interest
in what you do? How you do it?
The man never talked to me.
I never talked to him.
Well, thanks for your time.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
Hello.
What?
What do you think that is?
- An empty frame.
- Mmm-hmm.
Otherwise known as...
JEZZIE: A missing picture.
AGENT HICKLEY: You onto something?
- A missing picture.
- ALEX: Mmm-hmm.
Our Mr Soneji has a sense of humour.
He didn't just kidnap a little girl,
he turned it into a game.
Okay.
Let's see what you know, Mr Lindbergh.
- My, my.
- What did he get?
Dr Cross isn't in cyberspace any more,
you're at a live site
looking through a video camera.
Those arrows down there move it.
Where are we?
I would guess we're in Soneji's home.
Now we're supposed to find out
where that is.
WOMAN: Oliver McArthur's office.
Yeah, it's me. Hold on.
How about the files?
AGENT HICKLEY: There.
- On the wall.
- JEZZIE: There's a...
Can you zoom in there?
Yeah.
MCARTHUR: Jonathan...
- "M"...
- AGENT HICKLEY: "E"...
ALEX: Hold on. Hold on.
AGENT HICKLEY: "L"?
You can't move that around, can you?
It's stationary.
Go back.
ALEX: No, there's something
somewhere else. I'll guarantee it.
AGENT HICKLEY: Right there.
MCARTHUR: There.
JEZZIE: What?
AGENT HICKLEY: You can zoom.
MALE AGENT: Focus. There.
Bingo.
AGENT HICKLEY: M-E-R...
MALE AGENT: Merc?
ALEX: Mercusio.
M-E-R-C-U-S-l-O.
- MALE AGENT: 14-32... 35.
- 35.
- Granville.
Gary Soneji is also known as
Mercusio, Jonathan,
1435 Granville Street.
Well done, Alex.
(SIGHS)
AGENT: In! In!
Cover up. Zoom in! Left!
Eyes open!
There.
AGENT: Not until we get the go-ahead.
AGENT: Turn it out to the roof.
AGENT: Yeah, he's still dusting.
His surveillance was better than ours.
He's been at this for years.
ALEX: Imagine the patience.
The dedication.
You sound like an admirer.
Well, he's...
He's like a spider.
And I happen to like spiders.
AGENT:
He's got an elaborate setup, here, boss.
You want to see
how he stayed clean at school?
It laminates a plastic veneer
over your hands.
Look at this.
Foam rubber. Looks like
he was wearing prosthetic appliances.
REPORTER ON TV:
I understand the Secret Service
are being cautious tonight.
There is speculation
that a full investigation is underway
into how Gary Soneji
was able to kidnap a student
- from right under their cameras.
- (HORN HONKING)
Yes, Kevin.
One of the Secret Service agents...
Evening. What's the problem?
Help! Help me!
You've got a Rule 21 problem,
no running lights.
Again?
I just replaced the fuses yesterday.
Help! Help!
Sir, no running lights.
You're going to have to follow us in.
Help! Please, help me!
Well, let me see what I can do
with the fuse box. Hold on. Hold on.
I'm in here, help me!
I've been kidnapped, help!
Help!
How's that?
Thanks a lot, fellas.
Help!
Help me, please!
(SOBBING) Help me, please!
Help me!
"...and before the hood
was pulled over his head,
"he bragged to his executioner,
"'They think that when I die,
"'the case will die.
"'They think it will be like a book I close.
"'But the book,
"'it will never close."'
Soneji was quoting the final words
of Richard Bruno Hauptmann.
I'm sorry, I don't follow.
1932.
The infant son of Charles Lindbergh,
America's greatest hero, was kidnapped.
When Bruno Hauptmann was arrested,
what followed became known
as "The Crime of the Century."
I believe that Soneji
wants to do the same thing.
You think we're dealing with a copycat?
Something like that.
Dr Cross.
What does he want from you?
He's brought me in
and left this trail
because he wants me to make sure
that he's properly appreciated.
And in order for him to achieve this,
he has to kill Megan?
No, no. Not necessarily.
The death of the Lindbergh baby
was accidental.
Nevertheless,
it's critical that we pull his strings.
The more we make him a living legend,
the more likely he is
to keep Megan alive.
REPORTER: Dr Cross,
you've been brought into this case,
- what can you tell us about Gary Soneji?
- (CLAMOURING)
ALEX: I can tell you that
Soneji is very determined,
obviously highly capable
and we consider him
a serious adversary.
REPORTER 2:
What about Megan Rose?
ALEX: Megan Rose is Gary Soneji's ace.
As long as he has her, he's in control.
(RUNNING WATER)
REPORTER: Sir, would you assign
as many agents to this case
if she wasn't a Senator's daughter?
The size of our task force is a reflection
of who Gary Soneji is, not Megan Rose.
(BUZZING) Mr Soneji?
You can parse the words if you'd like.
Hello.
I need to go to the bathroom.
All right. Be right there.
No, not at this time.
(COUGHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Come on.
(FIRE EXTINGUISHER HISSING)
Hey!
Help!
Please, help!
Help me, please!
Help!
Help me!
Help, please!
Please, help me!
I'm coming!
Hold on!
Help! Help me!
(MEGAN SCREAMING)
No!
No! Please!
(SOBBING) Please!
Please!
No! Help me! Please!
No! Please!
(COUGHING)
Here. Here. (SHUSHING)
This'll keep you warm. There you go.
Megan, you promised me
you were going to behave yourself.
Because of you, what you've done,
that man is dead.
Now, promise me...
Promise me you're going to be
a good little girl, okay?
Say, "Yes, Mr Soneji."
(WEAKLY) Yes, Mr Soneji.
Okay.
(SHIVERING)
Now let's go have that cup of tea.
I'd say eight hours. About 9:00 a.m.
Slugs are large calibre.
Shots hit him here, here.
Kill shot tapped him, crown of the head.
This here is Thomas Mathias,
he found all this.
This way.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
She's not in the water, Jezzie.
Soneji still has her.
- There is no way of knowing that.
- Well, think about it.
Megan is precious cargo.
Soneji is not going to let
some twist of fate bring her harm.
Right?
But why Megan? Why her?
Come on.
- Where are you going?
- Back to the city. We'll talk in the car.
ALEX: You asked, "Why Megan?"
And that's the question we should
have been asking right from the start.
Why Megan?
Who is Senator Hank Rose?
- He's...
- Nobody.
Most people don't even know who he is.
Never heard of him.
Couldn't pick him out of a line-up.
This case is front-page news now,
where will it be in two months?
A year?
Oblivion. Know why?
Because Senator Hank Rose
is no Charles Lindbergh.
- Well, okay, then, who is?
- Ah...
There is the troublesome question.
Come on, Jezzie.
Two years, five days a week.
You know Soneji.
Who's a bigger fish than Megan Rose?
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Dr Cross, Agent Flannigan,
we appreciate your concern,
but Dimitri is fine,
and our security services
are most capable of protecting
the son of the Russian president.
Can we at least talk to him?
Nothing would please us more
than to be of help.
But speaking to Dimitri right now
would be inappropriate.
Thanks for your time.
What?
Well, McArthur is drag netting the bay,
right?
And, I mean, he's not really missing us,
so I was thinking
maybe we could just stick around and,
you know, scope out the place a bit.
Agent Flannigan, are you...
Are you suggesting a stakeout here?
Yeah, you know, stale coffee,
some doughnuts.
No, no, no. That's a first-class stakeout,
Agent Flannigan.
What you are talking about here
would be no frills.
You'd only get to think about
stale coffee and doughnuts.
Well, I can handle it if you can.
(SIGHING)
I get the feeling you've done this a lot.
Oh, yeah.
Every chance I get.
Especially when it's cold and wet.
No parking here.
We are on the clock, Officer.
Everything okay?
Everything is all right.
What's the problem?
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (GROANING)
Go ahead, Jezzie.
What?
Have one.
Thank you.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Alex, that's Dimitri.
Jezzie, it's him. It's him!
Soneji!
Hold it right there!
Jezzie, shoot the tyres!
Jezzie!
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
Police! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
DIMITRI: Jezzie!
Jezzie, you're going to
get Megan back, right?
Yes, we are. I promise.
Use this to get Mr Soneji.
I will.
Thank you.
You talk to Hal,
I want you to bring him up to speed.
Well done, guys.
Avert an international crisis
and paint Soneji into a corner.
Not bad for a night's work.
Incoming, Soneji ditched the patrol car
near Reno Park.
Hijacked a tan Sierra.
Put one bullet in the driver's head.
Last seen heading toward Route 50.
Annapolis. I knew it. 75,000 boats.
- Other marinas?
- We're here, dead fisherman here.
These, all the marinas, all locked down,
patrol boats in each of them.
All right, listen up. We got to move fast.
Roadblock Route 50 and
triple the surveillance in the harbours.
I want two choppers on the pad
in five minutes. Let's go.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Son of a bitch.
What's wrong?
I blew it, that's what's wrong.
I had a shot
right before he hit the hydrant.
But instead of pulling the trigger,
I was thinking. I was thinking!
Yeah, you were thinking of
the possibility of your shot going astray
and blowing Soneji's head off,
in which case...
We would never find Megan. I know that.
Well, then, don't beat yourself up
for being prudent.
Alex, you don't get it. I was trained
to shoot first and think later,
- and I...
- Jezzie, for heaven's sake.
If you hadn't convinced me to stay there,
Soneji would have two victims
instead of one.
Plus we'd have an international incident
on our hands. You did good.
- Yes, but still...
- You did good.
- Anything?
- No, not yet.
We're sitting on the area.
Chief, Soneji's on the phone.
- Soneji?
- SONEJI: Detective Cross?
I want to explain
how the agenda's changed.
You're going to bring me
$10 million in diamonds.
Point five carat, colour D, clarity Sl2
in a thermos in nine hours.
If the stones are rigged, laser tagged,
irradiated, the girl dies.
Does that penetrate?
It does.
I'll call back. 4:00 p.m. sharp.
(CALL DISCONNECTS)
He beat the trace.
The clock's ticking, people,
let's move this downtown. Let's go.
(CLINKING)
(PHONE RINGING)
SONEJI: Dr Cross?
I'm here.
The Watergate. 20 minutes.
There's a package for Mr Antwerp.
Okay, people, let's move.
ALEX: Don't lose me, kiddo.
You won't even see me.
(TYRES SQUEALING)
ALEX: I'm on police business.
Keep it here, please.
Eddy, this way.
Hi, how are you?
Do you have a package for Mr Antwerp?
Yes.
Yes, sir.
(MOBILE RINGING)
Over there. That one.
Cross.
SONEJI: Leave the phone.
Leave the car.
Pennsylvania and 6th. The fountain.
Fourteen minutes. Run.
Thanks.
Mac, you there?
- Alex.
- He made me ditch the car.
Looks like it's a running game.
I'm on my way to
6th and Pennsylvania.
I'm left and behind you, Alex.
Bearing onto Pennsylvania.
(PHONE RINGING)
- Cross.
- SONEJI: 12th and Madison.
Twelve minutes will get you there. Go.
Unit 3, loop on 23rd Street.
Unit 6, take K Street and double back.
You've got four units on top, Alex.
(PHONE RINGING)
Cross.
SONEJI: Four minutes. Union Station.
Main entrance.
Jezzie.
Union Station, main entrance.
(HONKING)
It's rush hour.
He's drawing him into a crowd.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey! Hey!
Don't answer that!
I think it's for me.
Cross.
(INDISTINCT
ANNOUNCEMENTS ON PA)
(MOBILE RINGING)
- Cross.
- Keep this phone. Take the Metro.
Platform A. You got two minutes. Go.
Jezzie, Metro, downstairs, platform A.
(MOBILE RINGING)
Cross.
Go to the centre of the platform.
Track 15. Go.
Go to the first car.
You there yet?
Yeah, I'm there.
Go to the left side. Open the window.
These windows don't open.
You're smart, Detective. Improvise.
Quickly.
Police officer, everybody down!
Get down, everybody down.
Come on, out of the way.
We're ready. All right. Now, throw.
MCARTHUR: We can neither confirm
nor deny that Gary Soneji
was involved in the incident
on the MTA train this morning.
REPORTER 1: We've heard rumours
that a ransom was paid.
Can you comment on this?
I can't comment on any of that.
REPORTER 2:
What about Megan Rose?
I'm not going to go into any details
at this time.
REPORTER 3: What do we know
about Soneji's state of mind?
I'm not going to comment
on his mental stability.
You can draw your own conclusions.
Now, Senator Rose has agreed
to make a statement, but he's not...
- What's up?
...going to answer any questions.
The file on Soneji,
is it still on your kitchen table?
Yeah, why?
I'm going to have another look at it.
This business
about the diamonds, money,
I didn't see it coming.
SENATOR ROSE: and the feelings
of absolute helplessness.
I am grateful that the FBI is here
with the objective expertise required
to find out where my daughter is.
Secondly, I now...
JEZZIE: This is worse than killing time.
Yeah, but you'd be amazed at how often
the small, neglected things
become the most important.
I've just got the feeling
we are missing something.
Maybe I'm in the wrong line of work.
Maybe I should take on something
less challenging.
You do what you are, Jezzie.
You mean, "You are what you do."
No, I mean, you do what you are.
You're born with a gift.
If not that, then you get good
at something along the way.
And what you're good at,
you don't take for granted.
You don't betray it.
What if you do betray your gift?
Then you betray yourself.
That's a sad thing.
(SIREN WAILING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
- Who is it?
- Police.
(GASPING)
Gary Soneji.
Hi, Alex.
Now, right hand, thumb and forefinger.
Just give me the gun.
Alex, you can't shoot me.
You'll never find Megan.
Sit down, Alex.
I'm a little concerned, Alex. I'm a little...
I'm a little worried that you...
You don't really care
to understand me any more.
That you won't paint an accurate portrait.
And I need you to convince me
that I'm wrong.
Well, in order to do that, we're going
to have to talk about Megan Rose.
No. No, no bargaining, Alex.
No cheap interrogation techniques.
It's transparent and it's clumsy.
This is between me and you.
I want you to see.
I want you to look inside here
and tell me what the fuck you see.
I'm a gift to you, Alex.
I'm a gift to you.
And you are beyond pitiful
if you cannot understand that.
I'm living proof that a mind...
The mind is a terrible thing.
(LAUGHING)
I see you've got
your sense of humour back.
Yeah.
I wondered what happened to it
during the ransom drop.
The ransom drop.
That was a well-earned $12 million.
Twelve million.
Senator Rose says he can pull strings.
Says he can fix it
so you keep the $12 million and walk.
All you have to do is return the child.
Where is Megan?
Where's Megan?
Where's Megan? Where's Megan?
She's trapped on my boat, Alex,
isn't that right?
Or maybe she's stuck
in a warehouse somewhere
or floating in a river.
Swinging from the end of a rope.
Buried alive.
(SONEJI CHUCKLES)
I envy her.
What would life have been like
with parents like that? (SNIFFLING)
Come on, Gary.
Blaming your parents for what you are?
I'm not blaming them, Alex.
They've been punished already.
Oh?
I burned down the house
while they slept.
I was 15 years old.
Was it what you expected?
Not really. It was a new experience.
What, killing?
No.
Being in the newspapers.
SONEJI: So, in your opinion, Doctor,
were my actions triggered
by nature or nurture?
If you want me to be brutally honest,
I think you just have a morbid desire
to burn in hell.
We're done for today.
I'm taking her with me.
(JEZZIE GROANING)
You're not taking her anywhere.
I'll send her back to you.
You just tell me
which piece you want first.
(SCREAMING)
SONEJI: Oh, shit! (GROANING)
Damn it!
Alex!
(GASPING)
What...
What have you done?
(SIRENS WAILING)
REPORTER: Residents of this
normally quiet suburb are still in shock
as news of the shooting of Gary Soneji,
who is America's most wanted man,
filter through their community.
Apparently Soneji attempted
to confront or even harm
members of the kidnapping taskforce
hunting him.
So he came after Jezzie
as payback for Dimitri.
Ostensibly, yeah.
That's how you want it on record?
Yeah, for now.
Here they come.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
Dr Cross, tell me you have
at least an idea of where my little girl is.
I'm sorry, sir, I can't.
You kill the one man
that has the answers,
and you're telling me you haven't a clue?
Not one clue?
The man walked in the fucking room
- and you shot him!
- MCARTHUR: Senator.
Standing in his shoes,
I'd have done the same thing, sir.
Well, that's your job, not his.
He's supposed to find my little girl,
not shoot the man
who knows where she is.
MCARTHUR: Senator.
It's not over.
The book is not closed.
Alex.
Thank you for saving my life.
Goodbye, Jezz.
You want to hear something funny, Mac?
Sure, cheer me up.
I congratulated Soneji
on scoring $12 million.
You mean $10 million.
Exactly.
He had no idea what I was talking about.
(DOOR OPENS)
I know you. You work at my school.
Eat your food, Megan.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Alex, where is this going?
MCARTHUR: We've been through
these tapes backwards and forwards.
I can't see how
this is helping us find Megan.
ALEX: Do you know what I see, Mac?
Someone was onto Soneji
long before we ever heard of him.
Look at this. What do you see?
Agent Devine hauling ass
out to the front gate.
Mac, he could have shut
this whole place down from right there.
Now you want to tell me why he didn't?
Good God!
Devine was in on it with him.
Then when Soneji hit the embassy,
he pulled a double-cross.
He ran his own ransom.
No.
Soneji was a loner.
An accomplice would have been
beneath him.
I'll tell you what happened.
Soneji was hoodwinked,
and so were we.
Details are still emerging,
but this much is clear,
the manhunt that began over a week ago
in the nation's capital
- came to a violent end late yesterday...
- (RATTLING)
...with the death of kidnapper,
Gary Soneji. In this...
JEZZIE: Don't move.
Turn around, hands on the wall,
feet apart.
Hi, Jezz, where did you come from?
You know something, Devine?
You're pretty stupid.
Your car in the driveway,
the TV so loud you wouldn't be able
to hear a SWAT team come in.
- What are you doing?
- Shut up!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Where's Megan?
She's in the barn.
She was so doped up,
I don't think she even knew
I took her off the boat.
She's still alive?
You were supposed to dump her
in the river after you got the diamonds.
Yeah, well...
Maybe killing a kid is something
I'm not prepared to do on my own.
Anyway, today, tomorrow, it's still
going to look like Soneji killed her.
She can't die after Soneji, you idiot!
It doesn't make any difference,
you know why?
They're never going to find the body.
Okay. I'll go do it now,
will that make you happy?
Yeah, it would.
Wait.
Can I see them?
(CLINKING)
Hey, do you realise
that we spent an entire year
following Soneji's every move?
I think we deserve these.
That beats the hell out
of a Secret Service pension, huh?
Hmm.
Profiling the profiler.
Kidnap from the kidnapper,
that's brilliant.
You are a genius, Jezz.
Genius has nothing to do with it,
I'm just good at what I do.
Well, it didn't hurt that everyone else
involved was a complete half-wit.
You think Alex Cross is a half-wit?
You really believe
that he shot Soneji to save my life?
Cross pulled the trigger
because he knew Soneji
didn't have Megan any more.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that sooner or later
he's going to figure it out.
He already knows
Soneji didn't run the ransom.
He is onto us already, isn't he?
No, he's not onto us.
But I think he's onto you.
JEZZIE: It's Turkish.
My daddy won it in a game of poker.
It's about as much as I know
about my father.
(MEGAN STRUGGLING)
Megan?
Megan, it's me, honey.
Jezzie?
Jezzie! Jezzie, I'm in here! Jezzie!
Open up, honey.
I'm gonna take you home. It's all over.
Yeah, sure, just hold on a second!
(PANTING)
Jezzie?
Yeah, honey?
What happened to that other guy?
He's dead, Megan.
You're safe now.
Open up.
Jezzie?
Yeah, honey?
Why isn't there anyone else with you?
Megan, it's me.
Now don't be scared of me.
Open the door.
Megan, I'm going to ask you
one more time to open the door.
Right now! Open the door!
Megan, open the door, honey!
Listen to me! Open the door!
Megan, open the fucking door!
Open it! Bitch!
(SCREAMS)
Stop it!
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
Very clever, Megan.
(MEGAN STRUGGLING)
Come on.
- (MUFFLED SCREAM)
- (SHUSHING)
Jezzie?
It's over.
Drop the gun.
Alex.
How did you, um...
Aces and Eights, Jezzie.
Plus your timing was a little off.
I watched the tapes.
You and Devine could have
stopped Soneji at the school.
Just like you could have stopped him
at the Russian embassy.
But you had a different agenda.
You know something, Alex?
When you said you do what you are,
you were right.
I'm living proof.
Put the gun down, Jezzie.
Would you kill another partner?
You're not my partner.
(GASPS)
You all right?
You are a very brave girl, Megan.
Who are you?
I'm a policeman.
My name is Alex Cross.
I'm a friend of your parents.
Can you take me to them?
Nothing would give me greater pleasure.
Could you...
Thanks.